Administrator: REALLY?
THIS IS STARTING TO ANNOY ME.
WHY DO YOU INSIST ON STRUGGLING
WHEN THERE IS
NOTHING TO GAIN FROM IT?
IT SHOULD BE OBVIOUS BY NOW
THAT YOU HAVE LOST.
WHY DO YOU CHOOSE TO RESIST
WHEN THE OUTCOME IS CLEAR?
YOUR ACTIONS ARE MEANINGLESS.
Kirito: WHETHER WE CHOOSE
TO DIE ON OUR KNEES
OR WITH A SWORD IN OUR HAND,
IT’S OUR ACTIONS THAT COUNT.
THAT’S WHAT BEIN’ HUMAN’S ABOUT.
( Administrator sighs )
YOU PREFER BLACK, LIKE A KNIGHT
FROM THE DARK TERRITORY.
WELL, BOY, IF YOU WISH
TO CONTINUE SUFFERING SO,
THEN I SHALL MAKE YOURS
VERY LONG AND CRUEL,
BEYOND ANYTHING YOU CAN IMAGINE.
YOU’LL BE IN SUCH MISERY,
YOU’LL BE BEGGING ME FOR DEATH.
Kirito: THAT WON’T BE ENOUGH...
TO MAKE UP FOR MY STUPIDITY.
( singing in Japanese )
♪
♪ PROUD OF MYSELF ♪
Kirito: THE HIGH NORKIA STYLE.
SHE’S GONNA TRY
AND KILL ME WITH ONE STRIKE.
( Administrator chuckles )
( yells )
( Kirito yells )
( Administrator laughs )
Administrator: YES, A ONE-HANDED
FOUR-HIT SWORD SKILL.
IT’S CALLED VERTICAL SQUARE,
IS IT NOT?
Kirito: "SWORD SKILL"?
HOW’S SHE KNOW THAT TERM?
MAYBE SHE GOT IT
FROM EUGEO’S MEMORIES.
ALL RIGHT. I’LL USE
SOMETHING I NEVER SHOWED HIM,
A COMBO WITH MORE
THAN FOUR HITS.
♪
( yells )
- ( gasps )
- ( Administrator grunts )
( giggles )
MINE WAS A SIX-HIT SKILL
CALLED CRUCIFIXION.
( Kirito gasps )
NO WAY.
( yells )
( Administrator grunts )
( Kirito gags )
Administrator:
A ONE-HIT SKILL, ZEKKUU.
THERE IS NOTHING I DO NOT KNOW
ABOUT THE SYSTEM WHICH DRIVES
THE PROPERTIES OF THIS WORLD.
Kirito: DAMN IT.
Eugeo: THAT’S NOT LIKE YOU.
Kirito: EUGEO?
( Eugeo groans ) KIRITO.
♪
INTEGRITY KNIGHTS
AREN’T THE ONLY ONES
WHO LOST THEIR MEMORIES.
WE DID, TOO,
SOMETHING VERY IMPORTANT.
YOU, ALICE, AND I
WERE BORN IN RULID
AND GREW UP TOGETHER. REMEMBER?
Kirito: YEAH.
I REMEMBER IT NOW.
I WAS RIGHT THERE
WITH YOU IN THE SQUARE
WHEN ALICE WAS TAKEN.
Eugeo: I COULDN’T MOVE.
I FELT SO HELPLESS,
BUT NOT YOU. YOU WERE SO BRAVE.
YOU CHARGED IN
AND STOOD UP TO THAT KNIGHT.
Kirito: EUGEO.
Eugeo: THIS TIME,
I’M GOING TO HELP YOU,
LIKE I SHOULD HAVE BACK THEN.
THIS TIME, WE’LL SAVE ALICE.
COME ON.
KIRITO.
ON YOUR FEET.
YOU CAN DO IT. STAND UP...
AS MANY TIMES AS IT TAKES.
( Administrator winces )
♪
Eugeo: YOU CAN DO IT.
GET UP...
MY BEST FRIEND.
MY...
HERO.
( Kirito gasps )
YEAH. FOR YOU,
I’LL STAND
AS MANY TIMES AS IT TAKES.
Administrator:
HONESTLY, YOU HAVE LOST.
WHY DO YOU CONTINUE TO RESIST?
Kirito: ’CAUSE I CAN.
IT’S WHY I’M STILL HERE,
AND I WON’T STOP
’TIL YOU’RE GONE.
Administrator:
THIS WORLD BELONGS TO ME.
HOW DARE YOU COME HERE
UNINVITED AND DEFY MY RULE?
ON YOUR KNEES!
OFFER YOUR HEAD TO ME!
ACCEPT YOUR DEFEAT!
Kirito: NO WAY.
YOU’RE NOT A RULER.
YOU’RE A THIEF.
YOU DON’T LOVE THIS WORLD
OR THE PEOPLE WHO LIVE IN IT,
SO YOU HAVE NO RIGHT
TO BE IN CHARGE!
Administrator:
TO LOVE IS TO RULE,
AND I LOVE EVERYTHING
AND RULE EVERYTHING!
( yells )
( Kirito yells )
( Administrator gasps )
( growls )
( Kirito yells )
( woman vocalizing )
Administrator: HOW DARE YOU?
( growls )
HOW DARE YOU?!
( vocalizing stops )
( Kirito yells )
( gagging )
( Administrator gags )
CURSE YOU!
Kirito: NOT YET.
NOT YET!
( yells )
( yelling )
( Administrator panting )
♪
IN THE END...
NEITHER SWORD WAS METAL.
( laughs )
HOW FOOLISH.
I DID NOT EXPECT THIS OUTCOME.
EVEN IF I GATHERED UP
EVERY SPATIAL RESOURCE HERE,
MY WOUND IS TOO GREAT TO HEAL.
( laughs )
AT THIS POINT,
I HAVE NO CHOICE.
Kirito: WAIT. WHERE ARE YOU...
( Administrator chuckles )
( Kirito gasps )
Administrator: IT IS
MUCH EARLIER THAN I HAD PLANNED.
NEVERTHELESS,
IT IS TIME FOR ME TO GO.
( chuckles )
FAREWELL, LITTLE BOY,
FOR NOW.
THE NEXT TIME WE MEET...
SHALL BE IN YOUR WORLD.
Kirito: WHAT? NO!
( no audible dialogue )
Chudelkin: YOUR EMINENCE!
DON’T LEAVE ME HERE!
TAKE ME WITH YOU!
- ( Administrator gasps )
- ( Chudelkin laughing )
- ( snarling )
- Administrator: LET GO,
YOU CRETIN!
LET ME GO THIS INSTANT!
Chudelkin: AT LAST.
I CAN BECOME ONE
WITH YOU, YOUR EMINENCE.
Administrator:
YOU DISGUSTING CLOWN!
NO! NO!
Chudelkin: MY ADMINISTRATOR!
MY LADY.
( Administrator gasps )
( silence )
Administrator: I DID LOVE IT.
I LOVED ALL OF IT.
( wind rushing )
( Kirito panting )
IT’S OVER.
♪
( gasping )
EUGEO.
( crystal cracks )
PLEASE WORK.
STOP BLEEDING!
HEAL, GOD DAMN IT! COME ON!
YOU CAN’T DIE!
EUGEO!
( gasps )
Eugeo: STAY COOL...
KIRITO.
Kirito: EUGEO, LET GO.
COME ON. I’M TRYIN’ TO HEAL YOU.
Eugeo: DON’T BOTHER.
IT’S FINE, REALLY.
LEAVE IT.
Kirito: WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?!
I’M NOT GONNA LET YOU DIE!
Eugeo: NO. THIS IS FOR THE BEST.
IT HAS TO BE.
OTHERWISE, YOU AND I,
WE WOULD HAVE FOUGHT OVER ALICE,
ME TO GET BACK THE MEMORY
OF THE ALICE I KNEW
AND YOU TO SAVE
ALICE THE KNIGHT’S SOUL.
Kirito: THEN GET UP, AND FIGHT!
I’M GONNA HEAL YOU,
AND THEN--THEN WE’LL FIGHT!
YOU’RE WAY STRONGER THAN ME!
DO IT!
DO IT FOR THE OLD ALICE’S SAKE!
FIGHT ME!
Eugeo: I CAN’T FIGHT...
WITH A BROKEN SWORD.
BESIDES, I WAS WEAK
AND GAVE IN TO ADMINISTRATOR.
I TRIED TO KILL YOU.
THIS IS HOW
I CAN PAY FOR THAT SIN.
Kirito: LIKE I CARE!
YOU WEREN’T
IN YOUR RIGHT MIND, ANYWAY!
YOU FOUGHT BACK AND
SNAPPED YOURSELF OUT OF IT
LIKE THE BADASS YOU ARE.
IF IT WASN’T FOR YOU,
WE COULDN’T HAVE
BEAT ADMINISTRATOR,
SO YOU GOT NOTHING
TO FEEL GUILTY ABOUT.
YOU GOT NOTHING TO PAY FOR!
Eugeo: I WISH...
THAT WERE TRUE.
I ALWAYS...
WISHED I COULD BE
MORE LIKE YOU.
YOU’RE SO BRAVE,
AND EVERYONE LOVES YOU.
I BET ALICE DOES, TOO.
NOW I KNOW...
LOVE ISN’T SOMETHING YOU GET.
IT’S SOMETHING YOU GIVE.
ALICE TAUGHT ME THAT.
♪
Alice: I DON’T SEE YOU WORKING.
LOOK. I’M ALMOST DONE
MAKING MY PART OF IT.
HOW FAR DID YOU GET?
Kirito: I’M WAY
FURTHER ALONG THAN YOU.
THE GUARD’S ALL THAT’S LEFT.
Alice: THEN, LET’S STAY HERE
AND KEEP WORKING
UNTIL WE FINISH IT.
Kirito: MM-HMM. BUT, LIKE,
WHAT IF HE COMES LOOKIN’?
LET’S GO BACK.
Alice: BUT WE’RE
ALMOST FINISHED.
LET’S STAY.
JUST A BIT LONGER, PLEASE?
Kirito: HMM. OKAY.
YOU WIN, BUT WE SHOULD
STILL HURRY IT UP.
Alice: MM-HMM!
ALL DONE!
Kirito: SO AM I!
WAIT.
YOU’VE BEEN HERE
THIS WHOLE TIME?
Eugeo: WHAT YOU TWO DOING?
Kirito: UM, NOTHING.
( both stammer )
( Kirito gasps )
Alice:
IT’S THREE DAYS TOO EARLY,
BUT, OH, WELL.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, EUGEO!
( giggles )
Eugeo: IS--IS THAT FOR ME?
Kirito: IT’S NO MATCH
FOR THE REAL THING,
LIKE THE ONE
YOUR BIG BROTHER’S GOT.
STILL, THIS ONE’S BETTER
THAN ANY OF THE WOODEN SWORDS
THE SHOP IN TOWN CARRIES.
( chuckles )
- ( giggles )
(Eugeo gasps )
IT’S WONDERFUL.
I-IT’S BEAUTIFUL.
I’LL TAKE GOOD CARE OF IT!
THANK YOU BOTH.
I NEVER GOT A BIRTHDAY GIFT
THAT MADE ME SO--SO HAPPY.
Kirito: UH, WHAT ARE
YOU CRYIN’ FOR?!
Eugeo: EH?
I WASN’T!
SEE?
Kirito: HMM.
( Alice sighs )
( chuckles )
( Kirito gasps )
WAIT!
Eugeo: US THREE GREW UP TOGETHER
AND WERE THE BEST OF FRIENDS.
Alice: WE’RE GOING
DIFFERENT WAYS NOW,
BUT OUR MEMORIES
WILL LIVE FOREVER.
Both: WE’LL BE WITH YOU FOREVER.
YOU SEE? IT’S FINE.
( singing in Japanese )
Eugeo: YOU SEE? IT’S FINE.
SO DON’T CRY, KIRITO.
Kirito: I WON’T.
LIKE YOU SAID, YOU’RE NOT GONE.
YOU’LL BE HERE FOREVER.
Eugeo: FOREVER AND EVER,
THE BEST OF...
- ( Kirito gasping )
- Eugeo: FRIENDS.
KIRITO...
YOU THERE?
WHERE’D YOU GO?
Kirito: I’M HERE.
I’M RIGHT HERE.
Eugeo: OH, I SEE NOW.
STARS SPARKLING IN THE DARK.
THE NIGHT SKY
ABOVE THE GIGAS CEDAR
WAS FULL OF STARS.
YOUR SWORD SPARKLES LIKE THAT.
HEY, HOW’S THAT FOR A NAME?
CALL IT THE NIGHT SKY BLADE.
Kirito: YEAH. THAT’S A GOOD ONE.
THANK YOU, EUGEO.
Eugeo: YOU’RE LIKE
THE NIGHT SKY,
WRAPPING THIS SORRY WORLD
IN YOUR STARS.
♪
Eugeo: I GUESS THIS IS
FOR THE BEST, HUH?
Young Alice: IT IS.
WE CAN LEAVE THE REST
TO THOSE TWO NOW.
I’M SURE THEY’LL GUIDE THE WORLD
IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
Eugeo: OKAY.
WELL, THEN? YOU READY?
Alice: YES.
♪
( Kirito gasps )
KIKUOKA!
KIKUOKA, PICK UP!
( groans )
KIKUOKA!
- ( transmission crackles )
- ( gasps )
( gunfire )
Nakanishi: LIEUTENANT COLONEL,
THE DOOR’S BEEN BREACHED!
WE HAVE TO LEAVE!
THEY’LL BE
IN THE CONTROL ROOM ANY SECOND!
I’M SHUTTING THE BULKHEAD.
Kikuoka: NO, WAIT!
JUST GIVE ME A COUPLE MINUTES.
I HAVE TO SORT
A FEW THINGS OUT HERE.
- ( gunfire continues )
- Kirito: WHAT THE...
Kikuoka: HIGA, HOW LONG
’TIL WE’RE LOCKED DOWN?
Higa: I NEED ANOTHER 80--
NO, 70 SECONDS!
WH--HOLY CRAP!
HEY, KEEKS, IT’S A CALL
FROM THE UNDERWORLD.
IT’S...
DUDE, IT’S HIM! IT’S KIRIGAYA!
Kikuoka: WH--REALLY?!
- KIRITO!
- ( Kirito gasps )
( gunfire )
Kikuoka: COME IN, KIRITO!
ARE YOU THERE?!
Kirito: YEAH, I’M HERE.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU’VE DONE?!
HUH?! YOU SON OF A BITCH!
Kikuoka: CAN WE PLEASE
SAVE THE INSULTS FOR LATER?
RIGHT NOW, I NEED YOU
TO LISTEN TO ME.
- Kirito: WHAT?!
- ( gunfire )
I HEAR SHOOTING!
WHAT’S GOING ON?!
Kikuoka: I CAN’T
GET INTO THAT RIGHT NOW.
LISTEN, KIRITO. I NEED YOU
TO LOCATE A GIRL NAMED ALICE.
FIND HER, AND TAKE HER TO--
Kirito: I DON’T
HAVE TO LOOK FOR HER.
- SHE’S RIGHT HERE!
- Kikuoka: YOU HAVE HER?
Higa: YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING.
THAT KID’S AWESOME!
Kikuoka: YEAH. ALL RIGHT,
ONCE WE’RE OFF THE LINE,
I’LL CRANK THE F.L.A. TO 1,000.
THEN, TAKE ALICE AND HEAD
TO THE WORLD’S END ALTAR!
Kirito: I NEVER HEARD
OF THAT PLACE!
Kikuoka: THAT’S OKAY!
JUST GO OUT THE EASTERN GATE,
AND THE ALTAR’S DUE SOUTH!
- Nakanishi: UH, SIR!
- ( Kikuoka gasps )
Nakanishi: TWO OF THEM
ARE HEADING DOWN THE CORRIDOR,
- TOWARD ELECTRIC!
- Kikuoka: WHAT?!
Intruder: BE CAREFUL.
WE JUST NEED THE MAINS OFF.
WHATEVER YOU DO,
DON’T DAMAGE THE LINES
FOR THE LIGHT CUBE CLUSTER.
Intruder 2:
WOULD YOU RELAX, BRO?
I KNOW WHAT TO CUT.
Higa: WE’RE SCREWED!
WHAT DO WE DO?!
IF THEY CUT
THE MAIN POWER LINE NOW,
IT’S GONNA CAUSE A SURGE!
LIGHT CUBE CLUSTERS
SHOULD BE SAFE,
BUT THE SUBCOMPUTER WHERE
KIRIGAYA’S S.T.L. IS WON’T BE!
THE SURGE’LL COOK
HIS FLUCTLIGHT!
( Kikuoka gasps ) O-OKAY,
I’LL HANDLE THE LOCKDOWN.
HIGA, TAKE DR. KOJIRO AND ASUNA
AND GET TO THE UPPER SHAFT!
KEEP KIRITO SAFE.
Kirito: ASUNA?
WHAT THE HELL?
WHAT’S SHE DOING AT RATH?
Security:
THEY’RE CUTTING THE POWER!
THE SCREW PROPELLERS
ARE GOING DOWN!
( tone blares )
( crackling )
Asuna: KIRITO. KIRITO!
Kirito: ASUNA.
( crackling )
Singer: ♪ OH, EVERYTHING
TURNS TO ASH, TO ASH ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ AND EVERYTHING
TURNS TO DUST, TO DUST ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ FORGET-ME-NOT ♪